MOMIN BIN SHAHID

<SOFTWARE ENGINEER/>

C M ····· +92 334 3526270

→ MominBinShahid@gmail.com

·· MominBinShahid.github.io



@MominBinShahid

Technical Skills

TECHNOLOGIES

- JavaScript (ECMAscript) and TypeScript
- HTML/HTML5 and CSS/CSS3
- SuiteScript 2.X
- Sass/SCSS
- SOL
- Markdown

CLOUD PLATFORMS

- NetSuite (ERP)
- Azure
- AWS

FRONT-END FRAMEWORKS

- ReactJS
- VueJS
- Ant Design
- Vuetify
- Angular
- Gatsby (SSG)

BACK-END FRAMEWORKS

- Node.js
- Rhino.js
- Express.js

TESTING FRAMEWORKS

Mocha/Chai

DATABASES

- DynamoDB
- ElasticSearch
- MongoDB
- MySQL

CODE AND TASK MANAGEMENT

- Git
- Jira

MORE

- Redux
- NPM
- AJAX
- Babel
- **ESlint**
- Webpack
- WordPress
- Bootstrap
- JQuery
- JSX
- Electron
- Serverless

PERSONALITY TRAITS

- Fast learner
- Leadership skills
- Orator
- Problem-solver
- Good oral skills
- Hard Worker
- Dependable
- Educator

Profile

An enthusiastic and curious software engineer with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and over 4+ years of experience (i.e. 1+ during B.S.C.S and 3+ years after undergraduate), building software-based solutions for clients and service-based/product-based companies, which involve quick learning of emerging and legacy technologies, precisely understand current systems, taking thoughtful decisions and by that producing quality results in critical timelines. Till now, only worked on closed-sourced projects now, started contributing to OSS

Education

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (BSCS) Bronze Medalist (3rd Position)

2014 - 2017

University Of Karachi - Karachi, Pakistan U.O.K Merit Scholarship Holder

Experience

SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Sep.2020 - Present

SECURITI.AI (FOUNDRI PVT. LTD.) - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

• Operating as a senior product development engineer, primarily working on the premier product of the company called Securiti.ai. (f.k.a privaci.ai). As the development team follows a module-based approach so, I mainly focus on Data Map/Data Catalog Module thus, principally working on the front-end using Vue.js and vuetify but also ingressing into the back-end which mostly consists of go-lang and beego framework

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug.2019 - Sep.2020

FOLIO3 PVT. LTD. - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Working as a Technical Consultant (full-stack engineer) for Oracle Netsuite ERP, providing technical support, automate tasks and processes (ERP functions), perform trouble-shooting and resolve customer issues
- Alongside automation, develop a product Human Resource Module (HRM) for NetSuite, that uses React.js as frontend and for backend APIs, we use NetSuite core modules

SOFTWARE ENGINEER I & II

Mar.2018 - Aug.2019

SCAYLE PVT. LTD. - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Working as a full-stack developer for U.S. based clients on School Management System and Bioinformatics Research related products
- Managed end-to-end service deployment on cloud-based solution
- Evaluate business needs and deliver feature development estimates
- Successfully delivered new features for maintenance projects, prototypes for potential projects within the estimated time

WEB DEVELOPER

Oct.2017 - Dec.2017

REMATCH STUDIOS (ADAMJEE TECH VENTURE) - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

· Create a website and social platform base for a game development studio, used WordPress as CMS for their one pager and blog

CUSTOMER RELATIONSHIP MANAGER

Dec.2015 - Mar.2016

AASHMAN TRADE AND LOGISTICS - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

• To look after any/all freight and other business affairs along with firm's website and portals, to generate sale and business through aggressive marketing and sale strategies independently to achieve or exceed assigned targets by the management of the Company

SALES AND MARKETING EXECUTIVE

Dec.2014 - Mar.2016

SEA LICENSING - KARACHI, PAKISTAN

• To manage agency's website and offer consulting, crew licensing, ship registration and other professional services to the seafarers within the international maritime rules & regulations